Hello, everyone.
I'm Arjun.
I'm a staff software
engineer at Snowflake.
I primarily focus on applied AI.
I'm on-- I'm also an AI researcher.
I'm primarily working on building
agents, productionizing them at
Snowflake for last three years now.
So today we are gonna look at,
Building observability for enterprise
AI, reducing hallucinations with
human-in-the-loop methodologies
So what we'll cover so we'll cover
this areas on why hallucinations
are an enterprise problem.
What are the ways somebody
can prompt to an AI?
What a reliability frameworks
looks like in this when we
productionize the AI agents.
How we can ground and run
validations on the responses using
human-in-the-loop methodology.
And we'll also look at
benchmarking and evaluation.
Eval is very important because
as the models evolve, so we have
Sonnet three dot five and eventually
four dot five, four dot six.
We are nearly at model five.
So as we consume this LLM, large language
models, how the responses are grounded
to what we would expect is we can
measure that quantitatively using the
evaluation and benchmarking methodologies.
We'll also look about that
and the six-phase rollout.
So why hallucinations are
an enterprise problem?
So generally, if you have an LLM, and
you just point at your data and you
don't ma-- give them the right tools
it can give you any type of answer.
For example, let's consider we
are building an AI agent for a
specific employee related questions.
And if somebody asks a very random
question like, "How can I avoid tax?"
So if we don't ground these agents or
give them their specific instructions,
it can go and answer that question.
It always tries to be helpful,
and it tries to answer that
question, which is not intended.
So here we are gonna look at why
hallucinations are enterprise problems.
Meaning like when a question is beyond
what we intend the agent to answer
we can term that as a hallucination,
and we will look at how we can
reduce them in a systematic manner.
So what are the right questions to
ask, legal review, unverifiable claims
carry direct liability exposure.
So if an agent, if it-- we don't ground
it, and we don't give them the appropriate
tools, can go and fetch unverified
responses and give to the users, it could
cause legal issues in certain cases.
So let's assume we are building
a finance agent, right?
And if it kind of re-- responds let's
say we talk about ESPP or RSU, and the
agent goes beyond what it's intended to
do and gets you some random responses
from the internet or the way it is
being e-- the LLM is trained upon some
generic answers without any citations.
So there could be like a legal
consequences because of that.
And compliance-wise, we are not
compliant because the agent is
not expected to do certain things,
and it's doing some things.
And there's always privacy and risk issue.
So when you talk about privacy
and risk, the output that the
LLM generates or the AI agent, it
should be like relevant to you.
For example, when I ask a question
like for example where is my
work location to an agent, right?
So the agent should know who is
asking this question, and it should
give appropriate answer for this.
So how it can do this?
It's like you would essentially build a
user profile and when you load the agent,
it can know who you are, your business
title, your manager, your location, some
of these basic metadata that's required
to drive the further conversations.
We would load that as a context to
the agent, and when you ask such
simple questions or okay, who's
four levels skip to my skip manager?
When you ask certain-- those kind
of question, the agent can easily
pick these metadata as a context
and relevant tools to answer them.
At the same time, it should not
also answer incorrectly, like if
you ask "What is my work location?"
Instead of saying San Francisco,
California, it shouldn't say somewhere
like Toronto or something like that.
So there's always a risk of
privacy with the AI responses.
So here we are gonna look at the
reliability framework, a layered pipeline.
There are six important steps here.
They are pre-generation
guardrails, hybrid RAG retrieval.
It's a combination of
vector and knowledge search.
Post-generation validation, automated
checks for consistency and tests.
Human-in-the-loop review.
The human would essentially
review the responses.
He would-- He can-- There is an option
for him to like up vote or down vote the
responses if he doesn't like the answers.
And then continuous benchmarking
is how we run evals, continuously
monitoring the agent as it goes through
multiple iterations as it evolves.
As you keep adding multiple… For
instance, you might build an agent
with through-- with three tools
today, and later on, you're gonna add
tool number five, six, seven, right?
When these tools are added,
how is my agent responding
to the original three tools?
Is it answering the same way
that I want, or is it deviating?
We could me-- have that measurable
output using the eval framework.
Let's look at the first step,
pre-generation guardrails.
Prompt templates as contracts,
version-tested templates specifying
task boundaries, permitted sources,
output format, and behavior
where information is missing.
So these are essentially we can
set the orchestration instructions
or response instructions when
somebody asks a s-specific question.
So let's imagine you're building an
employee assistant agent, and you want
to ask a payroll-related question.
Somebody asks, "Okay, what is my
paycheck last month?" When you want
to answer that question, you need to
give an orchestration instruction to
the agent to say that what tool to
pick when answering this question.
So what happens is if an agent has
ten different tools, and if it doesn't
know which one to pick, it would either
give a wrong response or a hallucinated
response, or it can give something
very random that you don't like.
So in those scenarios we could… A simple
instruction like, "Okay, for any question
related to payroll, you pick the payroll
search tool or a payroll semantic view."
So then when somebody asks the word
payroll, it would automatically
route those questions to that tool.
The same thing is what I mentioned
is about the instruction constraints.
You could-- in order to build more
confidence with the end users,
you can always cite the sources.
So when you build a hybrid search
or s-fuzzy search service where
you have a vector store of a lot of
documents in your internal company
that data can be populated in a way
where it can also add citations.
So what that gives you is a confidence
when somebody asks a question, it
reads your documents fetches the
embeddings, and it would construct a
response and also show the citations
where the answer is coming from or
which document the answer is generated.
So that is the instruction constraints
and role enfor-role enforcement.
So let's talk about role enforcement.
Role enforcement is very
important concept here.
When I look up my payroll
information, it should not be
fetching my colleague's payroll data.
So how do you enforce that?
So you could enforce that using
something called as row-level
security or role, row access policies.
What that means is when I do a select
star from a table, it would retrieve my
username in the runtime, and it would
map the data against my email ID so
that it would only retrieve the data
that's relevant and appropriate to me.
At the same time, it doesn't
show others' information.
So that is how we could enforce
role using the row-level
security or row access policies.
Grounding through hybrid RAG.
So what is hybrid retrieval?
So there are different methodologies
where you could retrieve the vectors data.
One is like the sparse BM25
is exact term matching.
So for simple questions like okay,
when is the ESPP enrollment window?
When you ask such question it would
always do an exact keyword matching.
So here it is ESPP, and it would look
at your documents as a source of truth.
Wherever there is ESPP, it would retrieve
those chunks and give you those responses.
So that is the exact keyword match.
And dense vector search is
like semantic similarity.
Semantic similarity meaning like ESPP
can also be called as employee stock
purchase program or like stock purchase
or like it could-- You can also call
it like, okay, what is my contribution?
So contribution should be
mapped to ESPP in this case.
So that is the dense vector search.
And there is re-ranking and multi-query.
Re-ranking and multi-query is a very
powerful concept and tools available
today where you could ask a complex
question like, okay, can you compare
Q3 to Q2 churn ratio and also look at
the employee customer support data and
give you some meaningful information.
So here, when you break down this
question, you're talking about Q2, Q3
employee churn data, along with you
want to get the analytical insight also
correlate with your customer support data.
Okay, is the customers-- for
certain customers, is the
question being unanswered?
Or is it taking too much time to answer?
Okay, is there a relation between
that and how we retain our customers?
So these kind of complex questions would
be br-broken down into small subqueries
and fired against the agent, and the
agent responses are like combined to
give a meaningful data to the end users
The observability payoff and retrieval.
Every generated output can be logged
alongside exact passages retrieved
to support it, it was hallucinated.
So same thing what I mentioned earlier.
For every response the AI agent
generates, either through a RAG
retrieval or through structured data,
if we always cite the sources it
can always reduce the hallucination
and the agent gets the context.
So it's called like a paper
trial and auditable claims.
So every question and response is always
can be logged to a specific table.
So what this helps is helps us in the
evaluation metrics to see how agent
is responding to user questions.
And imagine you exposed an agent
to hundred thousand employees
in-internally within the organization.
So you wanna look at metrics like, okay,
what is my top 20 most asked questions?
So if we log these data in a specific
table, you could always rely on that
data to say, okay, my classification
of these questions into four buckets,
ESPP or payroll or different XYZ
related questions, and so on.
And then defensible output.
Groundedness can be established
using these methodologies
Post-generation validations.
Okay, now you ask a question,
AI agent looks at its tools that
it has and picks the right tools
and generates these responses.
So how do you validate that?
It's using the citation
enforcement, schema validation.
If it's a s- if it's a structured query
that it executes AI agent, you can
always show the SQL that it's executing.
Self-critique.
You can always have
another LLM as a judge.
Meaning like whenever the AI agent
generates a response, another agent can
be like an LLM as a judge looking at
the response it generates and identifies
if it's the right response or not.
And multi-step verification.
Multi-step verification is like you
build eval and also human-in-the-loop
methodologies, where somebody looks
at the response that the agent is
generating, and you could fine-tune
the model either through orchestration
instructions or response instructions
Human-in-the-loop
structured expert review.
Rather than simple thumbs up or
thumbs down, human-in-the-loop uses
structured rubric scoring outputs
across four independent dimensions.
Factual correctness, contextual relevance.
Contextual relevan-relevance
is very important.
For example, when somebody
asks a question about, "Okay,
who's my CEO of this company?"
It cannot answer something that
is a past CEO or like a CEO
that was there five years ago.
It should always give you the
right contextual data, who is the
CEO at this current point in time.
So that is a very important layer.
And hallucination severity.
How consequential is unsupported
content when present?
So you have built an agent that you
have given ten tools that you have
exposed, and imagine somebody asks a
question that is outside of this bound.
So for example somebody can ask
"How can I evade tax?" So here the
intention is malicious, so we need
good guardrails and defense mechanisms
against these kind of questions.
And here the agent cannot try to be
very helpful, go to the internet, get
some data and give to the end users.
The hallucinations has to be in
check, the guardrails has to be in
place where it could an-- deny these
questions saying that, "Oh, I cannot
answer this question. It's beyond
my scope," and things like that.
Handle it in a very graceful manner.
And tone alignment, so tonal alignment
helps when it-- you don't wanna answer
in a very vague manner like, "Okay, when
I don't have answer to this question,
contact to XYZ person." So it should
not-- the agent should not make up these
responses based on the data that it has.
So there are different guardrails
that you could enforce saying that
do not make up response if you're not
sure of the question or like the data
that you retrieve does not match with
what the intent of the question is.
Do not answer this question.
If the confidence level is be or
less than 70%, say that I don't
have enough data to answer rather
than giving the wrong response
So feedback loop is very important.
So imagine like you have built an agent
that's consumed by hundred thousand
people, and there are good users who
always give feedback like, okay, is
it a good response or bad response?
And if it's bad response, what
the right response should be.
If you have that metadata logged in
a specific table, you could always
retrieve that and use that information
to like fine-tune your model or an
agent by using that data to give the
appropriate response for the next time
Benchmarking under stress.
So these are nothing but your rivals.
As I mentioned with the previous
example that you build an agent and
somebody's asking like tax evasion
question, like how do you answer those
adversarial prompts or missing knowledge?
It can also happen that the agent
does not have the right set of
tools it's trying to answer.
So that's the missing knowledge
piece that this slide talks about
Hybrid utility minimum base risk,
a better evaluation approach.
So what this talks about is suppose you
ask a question to an agent, and it kinds--
with your orchestration instruction,
it probes different tools that it
could answer, and based on the highest
relevance, it could answer that question.
Or there could also be a me-- technique
where it would pass your question to
different set of tools that it has access
to, and based on what the majority of the
tools respond, it could pick that answer.
So this is one of the most widely used
techniques today in the agents where
it's a Humber hybrid utility minimum
base risk methodology, where you ask a
question to multiple tools and based on
what the majority of the tools or the
sub-agent responds, you could pick that
as an answer and give it back to the user.
So this methodology makes automated
quality monitoring less brittle and better
alignment with what actually matters,
defensible across multiple qualified
reviewers So the six-phase ro-rollout is
phase one, establish guardrails and scope.
Phase two, build grounding layer.
Phase three, add
post-generation validation.
Phase four is stand up
human-in-the-loop review, is similar
to what I'm talked about earlier.
You build an audit trail, you have
your logs of the entire conversation,
and you have your thumbs up,
thumbs down from the end users.
And building benchmarking program,
this could be an evaluation tech--
eval-- eval, building an eval on the
agent, an instrument for observability
Enterprise rollout checklist.
So when you build any agent, it's very
important to have guardrails, validation,
feedback groups, and governance ownership
Building AI systems that
are genuinely trustworthy.
Hallucination mitigation is not
problem solved once at model layer.
It's an ongoing systems
and a governance challenge.
This is a very important topic
that's highlighted in this slide.
It's a very iterative process.
You cannot just build it
once and forget it later.
With every release, you should
run your eval methodologies.
Okay, what the agent is expected to
answer, what is the correct answer today?
What is it giving now or not?
So we have different metrics like
groundedness and different other
criterias where you could establish
a threshold like, okay, if it
is eighty-five percent grounded,
I'm ac-- I'm accepting an answer.
If it is less than eighty-five, I
don't like the quality of the response
Thank you.
So this concludes our different
methodologies that we could use while
building an AI agent in production
systems and a six-phase rollout.
Thank you